Guide to the Walter Thabit papers, 1950-2004
Thabit, Walter papers, 1950-2004
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Walter Thabit papers, 1950-2004.
4215
Walter. Thabit
72 cubic ft.
Project files, newsletters, administrative and financial records, and oral history interviews.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Files relating to projects with which Walter Thabit was associated include records of the Vest Pocket and Housing Rehabilitation and Model Cities programs in the East New York section of Brooklyn; planning papers and work files for consulting work in Hartford, Connecticut, and Newark, New Jersey.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
City planner.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Files relating to projects with which Walter Thabit was associated include records of the Vest Pocket and Housing Rehabilitation and Model Cities programs in the East New York section of Brooklyn; planning papers and work files for consulting work in Hartford, Connecticut, and Newark, New Jersey; proposals for a variety of projects both in the United States and abroad which never materialized; president's files of the Planners for Equal Opportunity; files on the development of new private ferry services to and from Manhattan, as well as Staten Island ferry planning; Health Pac newsletters, "Better Transit Bulletin," and Ekistics newsletters; and administrative and financial records of Thabit's planning consulting firm. Oral history interviews by Matthew Lyons, Nov. 17 and Dec. 13, 1988. Also, "Desperately Needed Now: An SRO Housing Revolution," 1991.
Also files on citizen participation, civil defense, school decentralization, Hoboken planning, single room occupancy (SRO), personal files, Cooper Square Committee files, and files relating to Planners for Equal Opportunity (PEO) and a collection of brochures and pamphlets on planning topics.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Thabit, Walter.; Lyons, Matthew Nemiroff,; Planners for Equal Opportunity.; United States.Model Cities Administration.; Vest Pocket and Housing Rehabilitation Program (New York, N.Y.)
Subjects:
City planning--New Jersey--Newark.; City planning--New Jersey--Hoboken.; City planning--New York (N.Y.); City planning--Connecticut--Hartford.; City planning--Societies, etc.; Ferries--New York (N.Y.); Housing--New York (N.Y.); Urban policy--New York (N.Y.); Urban renewal--New York (N.Y.); Political participation.; Civil defense.; Schools--Decentralization.; Single room occupancy hotels.; City planners.
Places:
Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)--Economic conditions.; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)--Civic improvement.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
See also the Planners for Equal Opportunity Records, #3943.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Biographical Materials
Series II. Administrative
Financial, Taxes and Mixed Records
Correspondence
Series III. Planning Projects
East New York
Hartford
Newark
Near East Projects
Freeport
East Flatbush
Powelton Village
Downtown Brooklyn Project
South of Houston (SOHO)
Poughkeepsie
Morningside Heights
Community Board
Methodist Hospital
Cooper Square
Small Projects
Series IV. Department of Transportation
Ferries
Handicapped
Reference
Administrative
City Streets
Small Projects
Safe Pedestrian Facilities
New Streets
Park and Ride
Series V. Organizations
Planners for Equal Opportunity (PEO)
Planning Network
Smaller Organizations
West Side Urban Renewal Area (WSURA)
Landmarks Preservation Commission
Series VI. Studies and Research
Study Proposals
Health
Education
Housing
Urban Renewal
Social Welfare
Planning Organization
Subject Files
Civil Defense (opposition to)
Miscellaneous
Articles and Reviews
Small Projects
Small Projects
CONTAINER LIST
- Contents (Box 1-62)
  Guide for Boxes 1-62. (3 MB Searchable PDF)
  Pages 2-7 are a key to abbreviations used for subjects in the collection.
- Series I. Biographical Materials
  - P-1: Bowling, Radio, A.C. (Box 43, Folder 20)
    Hobbies of Thabit
  - P-2: March 2, 1979 Collision, Also, 5/8/80, 1979-1980 (Box 43, Folder 21)
  - P-3: Sport Horse Investment (Box 43, Folder 22)
  - P-4: American Trans Air - Claim (Box 43, Folder 23)
  - P-5: PAN AM Claim (Box 43, Folder 24)
  - P-6: Mama's Book (Box 43, Folder 25)
    Edited by Thabit and Frances Foldin and published by Thabit.
  - P-7: Carol Watson (Box 43, Folder 26)
    An activist and good friend of Thabit
  - P-8: F. Thabit - Stock Analysis (Box 43, Folder 27)
    Former wife's stock holdings
  - P-9: Parking Vio. Bureau (Box 43, Folder 28)
    Fines
  - MIT Reunion (Box 65, Folder 23)
  - 1.06 Photogrammetry (Bound Folder) (Box 71)
  - Design - Lynch - MIT Notes (Bound Folder), Fall 1951 (Box 71)
  - Theory and Practise - Rodwin, Legislation - Kelly (Bound Folder) (Box 71)
  - MIT Notes (Bound Folder), Fall 1951 (Box 71)
  - "How to Look at Transportation Systems" (Bound Folder) (Box 71)
  - Mama's Book (Box 71, Folder 23)
  - MIT Alumni (Box 71, Folder 24)
  - Charcoal drawings by Thabit, undated (Box 73, Folder 6)
- Series II. Administrative (AD)
  - Financial, Taxes and Mixed Records
    - AD 1: State and Federal Quarterly (Box 12, Folder 1)
      Quarterly Employer Federal tax returns showing no employees during mid 1970's
    - AD 2: Loans (Box 12, Folder 2)
      Loans from banks and Beneficial Finance in an effort to stay afloat
    - AD 3: Insurance (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - AD 4: Disability Insurance and Workman's Compensation (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - AD 5: Quarterly Summary Forms (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - AD 6: Weekly Time Sheets (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - AD 7: Quarterly Federal Returns, 1969-1974 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - AD 8: W-2 Forms, 1969, 1974-1977 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - AD 9: New York City Withholding, 1966-1976 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - AD 10: Federal Unemployment Tax (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - AD 11: New York State Quarterly Unemployment (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - AD 12: Quarterly Federal, 1976-1978 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - AD 13: New York State Withholding, 1972-1975 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - AD 14: State Tax, 1976-1977 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - AD 15: Federal, New York State Taxes, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - AD 16: New York City Business Occupancy Taxes (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - AD 17: Payroll Books, 1970s (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - AD 18: Bills and Records, 1954-1956, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - AD 19: Bills, 1957-1963 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - AD 20: Bills, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - AD 21: Bills and Records, 1964-1971 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - AD 22: Paid Bills, 1972-1973 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - AD 23: Paid Bills, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - AD 24: Paid Bills, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - AD 25: Paid Bills, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - AD 26: Paid Bills, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - AD 27: Paid Bills, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - AD 28: Paid Bills, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - AD 29: Bank Statements, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - AD 30: Paid Bills, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - AD 31: Bank Statements, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - AD 32: Paid Bills, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - AD 33: Bank Statements, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - AD 34: Income Tax, 1951-1957 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - AD 35: Tax and Records, 1959-1961 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - AD 36: Tax and Records, 1962 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - AD 37: Tax and Records, 1963 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - AD 38: Tax and Records, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - AD 39: Income Tax, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - AD 40: Income Tax, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - AD 41: Income Tax, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - AD 42: Income Tax, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - AD 43: Income Tax, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - AD 44: Income Tax, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - AD 45: Income Tax, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - AD 46: Income Tax, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - AD 47: Income Tax, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - AD 48: Income Tax, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - AD 49: Income Tax, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - AD 50: Income Tax, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - AD 51: Income Tax, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - AD 52: Income Tax, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - AD 53: Income Tax, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - AD 54: Income Tax, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - AD 55: Income Tax, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - AD-34: Income Tax, 1982 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - AD-35: Income Tax, 1983 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - AD-36: Income Tax, 1984 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - AD-37: Paid Bills, 1982-1983 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - AD-38: Bank Statements, 1982 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - AD-39: Bank Statements, 1983 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - AD-40: Paid Bills, 1984 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - AD-41: Bank Statements, 1984 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - AD-42: Summary Time Sheets (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - AD-43: Closed Time Sheets (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - AD-44: Billing General (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - AD-45: Billings- Closed (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - AD-46: Poughkeepsie Administrative, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - AD-47: Cooper Square Administrative, 1970-1971 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - AD-48: Cooper Square Administrative, 1968-1969 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - AD-49: Cooper Square Contract (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - AD-50: East Flatbush Administrative (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - AD-51: White Plains Administrative (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - AD-52: Hoboken Administrative, 1970 (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - AD-53: Methodist Hospital Administrative (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - AD-54: Morningside Administrative, 1969 (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - AD-55: Manhattan Valley Contract (Box 26, Folder 22)
      Park of Morningside area.
    - AD-56: Morningside Administrative, 1970-1971 (Box 26, Folder 23)
    - AD-57: Freeport Administrative (Box 26, Folder 24)
    - AD-58: Planning Board #6 Administrative (Box 26, Folder 25)
      No File AD-59
    - AD-60: Evaluations Yearly & Other (Box 26, Folder 26)
      "A yearly agony over most of my consulting life."
    - AD-61: Master Mailing List, April 1975 (Box 26, Folder 27)
    - AD-62: Request for Reports (Box 26, Folder 28)
    - AD-63: Mailing Lists (Box 26, Folder 29)
    - AD-64: Meeting & Conference Locations (Box 26, Folder 30)
      Mostly Assembled for PEO (Planners for Equal Opportunities)
    - AD-65: Sample Letters, Forms (Box 26, Folder 31)
    - AD-66: Professional Services (Box 26, Folder 32)
    - AD-67: Misc. Equipment (Box 26, Folder 33)
    - AD-68: IBM Typewriter Manual (Box 26, Folder 34)
    - AD-69: Consultants, Draftsmen (Box 26, Folder 35)
    - AD-70: Employee Benefits (Box 26, Folder 36)
    - AD-71: Sanborn & Other Map Services (Box 26, Folder 37)
    - AD-72: Graphic Design (Box 26, Folder 38)
    - AD-73: Flatlands Proposal (Box 27, Folder 1)
      First proposal for work since Thabit became a consultant
    - AD-74: Brochure Materials (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - AD-75: Brochure Revision (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - AD-76: Employment Applications (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - AD-77: Paid Bills, 1985 (Box 42, Folder 14)
    - AD-78: Paid Bills, 1986 (Box 42, Folder 15)
    - AD-79: W. Thabit Bus. Exp., 1987 (Box 42, Folder 16)
    - AD-80: Paid Bills, 1988 (Box 42, Folder 17)
    - AD-81: Income Tax, 1985 (Box 42, Folder 18)
    - AD-82: Income Tax, 1986 (Box 42, Folder 19)
    - AD-83: Income Tax, 1987 (Box 42, Folder 20)
    - AD-84: Return - Amended, 1987 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - AD-85: Income Tax, 1988 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - AD-86: Bank Statements, 1985 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - AD-87: Bank Statements, 1986 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - AD-88: Money market Account (Chemical) (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - AD-89: Bank Statements, 1987 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - AD-90: Bank Statements, 1988 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - AD-91: Sylvan Lawrence Co. 305 Broadway, 1976 (Box 43, Folder 8)
      Thabits office beginning in 1976
    - AD-92: Miscellaneous - Administration (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence
    - AD-93: Incoming Letters, 1958-1959 (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - AD-94: Outgoing Letters, 1959-1960 (Box 45, Folder 13)
    - AD-95: Incoming Letters, 1960-1962 (Box 45, Folder 14)
    - AD-96: Outgoing Letters, 1960-1962 (Box 45, Folder 15)
    - AD-97: Incoming Letters, 1963-1964 (Box 45, Folder 16)
    - AD-98: Outgoing Letters, 1963-1964 (Box 45, Folder 17)
    - AD-99: Incoming Letters, 1965-1966 (Box 45, Folder 18)
    - AD-100: Outgoing Letters, 1965-1966 (Box 45, Folder 19)
    - AD-101: Incoming Letters, 1967-1968 (Box 45, Folder 20)
    - AD-102: Outgoing Letters, 1967-1968 (Box 45, Folder 21)
    - AD-103: Incoming Letters, 1969 (Box 45, Folder 22)
    - AD-104: Outgoing Letters, 1970 (Box 45, Folder 23)
    - AD-105: Incoming Letters, 1970 (Box 45, Folder 24)
    - AD-106: Outgoing Letters, 1971 (Box 45, Folder 25)
    - AD-107: Incoming Letters, 1971 (Box 45, Folder 26)
    - AD-108: Outgoing Letters, 1971 (Box 45, Folder 27)
    - AD-109: Writing Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 45, Folder 28)
    - AD-110: Incoming Letters, 1972 (Box 45, Folder 29)
    - AD-111: Outgoing Letters, 1972 (Box 45, Folder 30)
    - AD-112: Incoming Letters, 1973 (Box 45, Folder 31)
    - AD-113: Outgoing Letters, 1973 (Box 45, Folder 32)
    - AD-114: Incoming Letters, 1974 (Box 45, Folder 33)
    - AD-115: Outgoing Letters, 1974 (Box 45, Folder 34)
    - AD-116: Correspondence, 1975 (Box 45, Folder 35)
    - AD-117: Incoming Letters, 1976 (Box 45, Folder 36)
    - Copied Letters, 1958-1976 (Box 69, Folder 6)
- Series III. Planning Projects
  - East New York (ENY)
    - ENY-1: Original Proposal and Contract (Box 1, Folder 1)
      This file contains our original proposal to provide services to the Vest Pocket and Housing Rehibilitation program and our contract and possibly amendments to it.
    - ENY-2: Pre-Phase I Plans (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Proposals for the area submitted by community, private developers and the city. (Phase I refers to Vest Pocket and Housing Rehabilitation Program. Phase II refers to Model Cities.)
    - ENY-3: Social History of East New York (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Includes Demographic Change texts.
    - ENY-4: Landlord Meetings (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Information regarding meetings and interest in rehabilitating their buildings.
    - ENY-5: Housing Surveys (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Results shown in PFTTA-ENY (Planning for the Target Area-East New York)
    - ENY-6: Community Organization Questionnaire (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Questionnaire and its development. Includes organizations that are closed.
    - ENY-7: The Initial Plan (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Includes questions, amendments and Planning Commission Hearings.
    - ENY-8: Development of the Plan (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Background information, reports, and issues.
    - ENY-9: The Phase I Plan (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Background information leading up to it. Phase II files included to demonstrate which parts of Phase I were kept.
    - ENY-10: Weekly Meetings (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Information on meetings starting before contract was made final through the approval of the plan and beyond.
    - ENY-11: Phase I Plan Implemenation (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Leading up to, during and after implementation of plan. Concludes with report on community facilities (file 17). Continuous fight for control of program with Model Cities Committee.
    - ENY-12: Phase I Plan Implemenation, (1 of 5), 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - ENY-13: Phase I Plan Implemenation, (2 of 5), 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - ENY-14: Phase I Plan Implemenation, (3 of 5), 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - ENY-15: Phase I Plan Implemenation, (4 of 5), 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - ENY-16: Phase I Plan Implemenation, (5 of 5), 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - ENY-17: Community Facilities Implementation Report (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Vest Pocket Plan. All proposals, rejected and implemented, reported on here.
    - ENY-18: Post Phase I Plan Adoption Issues (Box 1, Folder 18)
      Wide variety of questions from factories that wanted to expand to newly proposed government facilities.
    - ENY-19: Preserving Buildings (Box 1, Folder 19)
      Watching out that buildings they wanted to rehabilitate weren't torn down under another government program. Some buildings were lost.
    - ENY-20: Phased Relocation (Box 1, Folder 20)
      The Plan called for phased relocation but the city decided to move forward all at once. The file reflects the monitoring of the process and reports on it.
    - ENY-21-22: ENY Model Cities Contracts (Box 1, Folder 21-22)
      Includes sub-contracts for the palnner doing Brownsville under our direction and for the architectural team working on it. Folder 22 includes an example of vouching
    - ENY-23: Subject Files of Planning Process (Box 1, Folder 23)
      Includes police, fire and library studies.
    - ENY-24: Phase II Guided by Phase I (1 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 24)
      Contrains materials going back to Phase I which were used to assist in Phase II. Includes Proposed government improvements and draft proposed community facilities improvements.
    - ENY-25: Phase II Guided by Phase I (2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - ENY-26: Early Childhood Centers (Box 1, Folder 26)
      East New York and Brownsville
    - ENY-27: Local Interest in Health Facilities, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      Minutes and correspondence of groups meeting in ENY such as Mental Health Committee, Model Cities Health Committee, ENY Housing, Urban Planning Committee and many health providers.
    - ENY-28: Research on Hospital Needs in ENY (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Planning Proposals and research relating to hospital needs in East New York.
    - ENY-29: Studies for Health Facilities (Box 2, Folder 2)
      More studies and proposals for health facilities, much of which go back to Phase I.
    - ENY-30: Recreational Facilities for ENY (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Plans and Programs for major recreation centers according to wishes of community. (Few if any of the recommendations made as a result of Model Cities were implemented.
    - ENY-31: Sanitary Challenges and Actions of ENY (Box 2, Folder 4)
      This file calls attention to the problems and steps taken by the community to do something about the lackadaisical sanitation practices in the area.
    - ENY-32: Traffic and Transportation (Box 2, Folder 5)
      Linear City
    - ENY-33-34: Northwest ENY Industrial Quadrant (Box 2, Folder 6-7)
      Report on industrial survey conducted in Phase I, the interview and structural survey forms used to develop the data, reactions and other information from interested groups.
    - ENY-35: Survey Forms from Phase I (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - ENY-36: Housing Survey Forms (Box 2, Folder 9)
      Used for special purposes and interview forms for owner occupants.
    - ENY-37: Phase II Major Structural Survey (Box 2, Folder 10)
      Housing type survey, a sampling to be studied in greater depth and architectural notes on rehabilitability.
    - ENY-38: Available Rehabilitation Programs (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - ENY-39: Segregated Schools and School Planning in ENY, 1966-1970 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      Approach to school planning and some materials on other items also found. New theories ilke the educational park, small schools and new learning processes were taking hold and people were demanding changes. In Brownsville and ENY, literacy was rare, dropouts endemic.
    - ENY-40: School Data (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - ENY-41: Reports on ENY School Reports (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - ENY-42: Broad Range of Issues (Box 2, Folder 15)
      This file contains issues from finding additional space to community control.
    - ENY-43: School Siting (Box 2, Folder 16)
      Each new school was proposed, site was carefully evaluated and yet the Board of Educations site proposals were still poorly thoughtout.
    - ENY-44: East Brooklyn High School Site Fight (Box 2, Folder 17)
      A high school that was never built even though four spare blocks of housing were demolished to make room for it.
    - ENY-45: Demanding Educational Parks (Box 2, Folder 18)
      First demanded in Brownsville than other communities like ENY. File contains legal papers for the suit to force the Board of Education to build an educational park in Brownsville.
    - ENY-46: Educational Complexes (Box 2, Folder 19)
      Various material discussing educational complexes including educational parks.
    - ENY-47: Linear City (Box 2, Folder 20)
      A scheme to combine an educational park with a needed expressway leg. This plan was met with opposition from all sides and areas that is was dropped.
    - ENY-48: Spring Creek Educational Park Scheme (Box 2, Folder 21)
      Proposed educational park, 2 miles out of ENY, that died a natural death.
    - ENY-49: Planning Educational Park in ENY (Box 2, Folder 22)
      ENY community obtained a contract to undertake a charrette to plan an educational park. None of the schemes were built.
    - ENY-50: ENY Community College (Box 2, Folder 23)
      Details on efforts to get a community college and urban center satellite into East New York.
    - ENY-51: Planning Files for Phase II (Box 2, Folder 24)
      Programming notes and attempts to see that money was reasonably invested.
    - ENY-52: Background Information (Box 2, Folder 25)
      Olio and Presentation notes.
    - ENY-53: Background information (Box 2, Folder 26)
      Reports from various surveys, mostly housing related
    - ENY-54: Background Information (Box 2, Folder 27)
      Proposal of a group of merchants and ENY type "entrepreneurs" who wanted to carve out a bit of real estate for themselves.
    - ENY-55: Background Information (Box 2, Folder 28)
      Minutes of meetings with the ENY Model Cities Physical Development Committee which aws responsible for approving the final plan.
    - ENY-56: Background Information (Box 2, Folder 29)
      Mostly background but includes findings of the industrial survey.
    - ENY-57: Draft of Phase II (Box 2, Folder 30)
      Plan, criticism and attempted modifications by city agency and central model cities.
    - ENY-58: 8 Reports and Open Letters (Box 2, Folder 31)
      Based on formal reports on the issues.
    - ENY-59: 3 Versions of Phase II Plan (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Signed verson is the approved plan.
    - ENY-60: City Planner Draft Training Program (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Never funded or approved but at least 3 ENY men active in the planning effort ultimately went to planning schools and became MCPs.
    - ENY-61: Model Cities Program (Box 3, Folder 3)
      Background on the Model Cities Program.
    - ENY-62: Physical Development Committee (Model Cities) (Box 3, Folder 4)
      Materials about the Physical Development Committee, largely during the finalization of Phase II plan.
    - ENY-63: Community Committee Materials, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      Minutes, meeting notices, organizational leaflets, newsletters.
    - ENY-64: Community Committees from 68'-70', 1968-1970 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      Meeting minutes, notices, letters, communications, issues, etc.
    - ENY-65: ENY Materials (Miscellaneous) (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - ENY-66: ENY Materials (Miscellaneous) (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - ENY-67: ENY Materials (Miscellaneous) (Box 3, Folder 9)
      Could be classified with planning files 51-56
    - ENY-68: Brooklyn Model Cities Committee (Box 3, Folder 10)
      Unnecessary bureaucracy, competition and destructive layer of Model Cities.
    - ENY-69: Central Brooklyn Model Cities (Box 3, Folder 11)
      Material coming out of the Central Brooklyn Model Cities Office.
    - ENY-70: Central Brooklyn Staff Reports (Box 3, Folder 12)
      Housing based on the work Walter Thabit and other consultants were doing
    - ENY-71: Vest Pocket and Rehabilitation Program (Box 3, Folder 13)
      City reports on implementation of the Vest Pocket and Rehabilitation Program
    - ENY-72: Central Brooklyn Model Cities Redundancy (Box 3, Folder 14)
      More consultants to undertake specific tasks that only served to cloud issues and duplicate efforts that never made their way down to the local Model Cities Committee leve.